## **JOE KAIS**

### 11847 BOULDER CRESCENT, WINDSOR, ONTARIO N8P1Z4

Telephone: 519-962-8500 Email: jkais@cogeco.ca www.linkedin.com/in/joe-kais-a4b11628

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a highly organised, resourceful and personable Food and Beverage Professional. I have an enthusiastic and flexible approach to my work with the ability to multi-task whilst maintaining exceptional quality and detail, making me a reliable and hard-working asset to any team. My national and international experience is a great asset to my employer and compliments my work.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# DECEMBER 2014- OCTOBER 2020 Mazaj Mediterranean Grill Restaurant General Manager Windsor

- Grand and soft opening fully licensed 60 indoor seating's and 30 outdoor restaurants
- Day to day operations
- Menu engineering and wine paring
- Standard recipes and implementation
- Establish and set up new suppliers accounts
- Proper equipments for new restaurant
- Local marketing and advertising soft and grand opening

## OCTOBER 2012- OCTOBER 2014 Midfield Concession Enterprise

Food & Beverage Manager/ Consultant Michigan- Detroit USA

- In charge of purchasing and special projects as assigned by the Director of operations
- Introduced new Food & Beverage products to boost sales
- Established and implemented standard operating procedures for inventory management control and F&B cost control systems for thirty four units within the company
- Responsible for creating new menus and wine pairing in coordination with suppliers and quality control for the company nation wide

### NOVEMBER 2010 – SEPTEMBER 2012 Byblos Hospitality Group

Group training manager- Dubai UAE

- Conducted training seminars for new and current employees including safe food handling, room service training, and how to up sell special products.
- Hiring and orientation of all staff for the group
- Familiarizing Room Division Managers with the F&B departments
- Involved and consulted in opening of all new outlets for the company
- Involved in upgrading all food & beverage cost control systems
- Continued quality improvements for five hotels, and two catering companies

### OCTOBER 2009 - OCTOBER 2010

#### **Taza Is Fresh Restaurant**

General Manager-Windsor

- Established suppliers accounts and forecasting sales
- Created a custom made menu
- Trained kitchen and service staff
- Established all accounting systems and payroll
- · Responsible for overseeing both soft and grand opening
- Established inventory control system

## 1983-2008

• Worked in the capacity of Food and Beverage manager in various hotels and restaurants

## **EDUCATION/CERTIFICATES**

JUNE 2010 St. Clair College of Applied Arts and Technology, Windsor Ontario

Hotel and Restaurant Management Diploma

(Leadership award)

JUNE 1987 American Hotel & Lodging Educational Institute USA

Specialization in Food and Beverage Management

# PERSONAL INFORMATION / INTERESTS

- An adaptable team player who is able to work under pressure and meet deadlines
- Efficient and accurate communication throughout all levels
- I enjoy running, cooking, and creating new recipes

## **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

- Serv Safe
- Standard First Aid CPR/AED Level C
- Smart Serve St. Clair College Windsor, ON
- Service Excellence Ontario Tourism Education Council
- Safe Food Handling Basic FST Training Training & Certificate
- Product Knowledge LCBO Level One St. Clair College Windsor, ON